Finding Aid for American Association for the Comparative Study of Law records, 1950-1972
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
American Association for the Comparative Study of Law records
1950-1972
American Association for the Comparative Study of Law.
8523 Bo 2
Records of the editor of the journal of the American Association for the Comparative Study of Law.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
27 linear feet
The records were transferred to the library from the Legal Research Department of the Law School of the University of Michigan (donor no. 5288 ).
No further additions to the records are expected.
The record group is open to research.
In 1951, representatives from ten law schools and the American Foreign Law Association joined together as the first sponsor members of the American Association for the Comparative Study of Law. The name was later changed to the American Society of Comparative Law. In 1952, the organization began publishing the American Journal of Comparative Law.
These are the records primarily of editors of the American Journal of Comparative Law. From 1951 to 1966, University of Law School professor Hessel Yntema was editor. He was also vice president of the association. Yntema was followed as editor by professor Alfred Conard. The records include manuscripts of writings submitted to the journal, board of directors' minutes, correspondence, treasurer's reports, and topical files. Much of these files remain unprocessed.
Subjects:
Law.
- Organizational records
  - Manuscripts (by author) [A-P], 1958 (Box 1)
  - Manuscripts [Q-Z] (Box 2)
  - Sponsor Members [A-C] (Box 2)
  - Sponsor Members [C-Z] (Box 3)
  - Manuscripts, 1953-1957 (Box 4)
  - Kurt Nadelmann Correspondence, 1954-1961 (Box 4)
  - Hessel Yntema, Memorial Volume, 1960-1961 (Box 4)
  - International Association of Legal Science (Box 4)
  - American Journal of Comparative Law Annual Meetings, 1951-1970 (Box 5)
  - Board of Directors, 1951-1969 (Box 5)
  - Treasurers Reports, 1954-1962 (Box 5)
  - Correspondence, 1953-1956 (Box 6)
  - Sustaining members (Box 6)
  - Basic Documents (Box 6)
  - Treasurers Reports, 1951-1968 (Box 6)
  - Memoranda (Box 6)
  - Preliminary Documents, 1950-1951 (Box 6)
  - Research in Inter-American Law, 1942-1943 (Box 6)
  - American Foreign Law Association meeting, 1957 (Box 6)
  - Teaching material (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 7)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 8)
  - Alfred Conard Files on American Journal of Comparative Law (Box 9)
  - Administration, including Foreign Student Folders (Box 10)
  - Administration, including Foreign Student Folders (Box 11)
  - Administration, including Foreign Student Folders (Box 12)
  - Administration, including Foreign Student Folders (Box 13)
  - Administration, including Foreign Student Folders (Box 14)
  - Correspondence (Box 15)
  - Correspondence (Box 16)
  - Correspondence (Box 17)
  - Correspondence (Box 18)
  - Correspondence (Box 19)
  - Correspondence (Box 20)
  - International Association of Legal Science (Box 21)
  - International Association of Legal Science (Box 22)
  - International Academy of Comparative Law (Box 22)
  - American Association of Comparative Law (Box 22)
  - Sponsor Members (Box 22)
  - Luxemburg International University of Comparative Sciences (Box 23)
  - State Department Advisory Committee on Private International Law (Box 24)
  - International Institute for Unification of Private Law (Box 24)
  - International Encyclopedia of Comparative Law (Box 24)
  - Hessel Yntema private letters (Box 24)
  - Hessel Yntema Memorial Issue (Box 24)
  - American Journal of Comparative Law (Box 24)
  - Hessel Yntema's manuscript articles, including correspondence (Box 25)
  - Hessel Yntema's manuscript articles, including correspondence (Box 26)
  - International Associations (Box 27)
  - International Committee on Comparative Law (Box 27)
  - International Institute for Unification of Private Law (Box 27)
  - International Colloquium at Paris, 1953 (Box 27)
  - Annual Research Reports to University of Michigan (Box 27)
  - Research Budgets (Box 27)
  - Correspondence, 1949-1950 (Box 27)
  - 3rd International Congress (Box 27)
  - Conference on Science, Philosophy and Religion (Box 27)
  - Survey Course on American Legal Institutions (Box 27)
  - Conflict of Law Course (Box 27)
  - Bar Exams (Box 27)
  - Alien Enemy Property (Box 27)